# Dev Agrawal

GitHub: github.com/devagrawal09 LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/dev-agrawal E-mail: <u>agrawadv@mail.uc.edu</u>
Website: devagr.me

## **Summary**

Software Developer with 5 years of experience, aspiring software architect and content creator.

## **Technical Skills**

Languages: JavaScript and TypeScript, Python (Django), C# (.NET Core), Java (Spring), PHP, HTML and CSS

Web: React (Next, Remix, Gatsby), Svelte, Vue, Angular, Express, Nest, Socket.io

Enterprise: Architecture and Design, Microservices, Domain-Driven Design, t

Cross platform: Ionic, React Native, Electron, PWA

Tools: Cloud (Heroku, AWS, Azure, Netlify, Cloudflare, Vercel, Firebase), Database (SQL, MongoDB, Redis),

**DevOps** (GitHub, Travis), **SysAdmin** (Linux, Docker, Nginx, Ansible)

Project Management: Agile, Scrum, Kanban, CI/CD

# **Work Experience**

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER (UC IT SOLUTIONS CENTER)

(Jan 2020 – Aug 2020, Jan 2021 - Current)

- Full-stack development of enterprise-level systems used by agencies throughout the country
- Led the development of the **Ohio Sentencing Data Platform** in collaboration with the **Ohio Supreme Court**
- Led the work on a suite of applications used by UC Corrections Institute and Department of Youth Services
- Assisted with DevOps, System administration, Quality Assurance, Monitoring and Client support

#### **RESEARCH ASSISTANT (UNIVERSITY OF CINCINNATI)**

(Sep 2018 – Dec 2019)

- Worked on a research project funded by NSF and Mozilla with a team of professors and masters students
- Researching the implementation feasibility of access control, emergency detection and crisis response using IoT

#### MOBILE DEVELOPER (HEALTHYLOVEDONES)

(May 2019 – Aug 2019)

**Created a mobile application** that greatly improved customer engagement

## FREELANCE DEVELOPMENT WORK (HEALTHYLOVEDONES)

(Apr 2018 – Jul 2018)

**Developed a web application** for the organization

## **INTERNSHIP FOR BHARAT VIKAS PARISHAD**

(Feb 2017 – May 2017)

Designed a web application for Bharat Vikas Parishad (Shiva Branch, Varanasi) for internal use

# **Projects**

## **HACKATHON SUITE (Lead Developer)**

- Suite of applications to aid hackathon organizing with **marketing**, **judging**, **registration**, **hacker matching** etc.
- Service-based backend leveraging cloud services (AWS, Heroku, Netlify, Cloudflare)
- Frontends built with Jekyll, React, and Angular
- My contribution conceptualized, architected, and developed most of this system

## **OHIO SENTENCING DATA PLATFORM (Senior Developer)**

- Collaboration with the Ohio Supreme Court
- For courts to record and analyze data about criminal sentencing cases
- Custom built engine to generate complex forms with real-time capabilities, analyzable data outputs, and docx exports based on JSON schemas
- Integration with legacy systems to pull data
- My contribution developed most of the system from scratch including the most complex features

### **DEVTRANET** (Senior Developer)

- Networking platform for engineers, investors, entrepreneurs etc.
- Discovering events, posting blogs, showcasing projects, finding jobs, and social media
- Frontend with React and Tailwind, Microservice backend with Next.js (Serverless) and Socket.io
- My contribution architected and developed all of the backend to be modular and optimized for serverless

## **HEALTHYLOVEDONES (Solo Developer)**

- A job portal for caregivers and those in need with built in hiring, communication, and payment system
- Holistic caregiver profiles based on professional and personal skills
- Mobile-ready full stack application built with Meteor
- ▶ My contribution developed all of the system

## **Education**

## **BACHELOR'S DEGREE – UNIVERSITY OF CINCINNATI**

(Aug 2018 – May 2023 expected)

- BS in Information Technology, Software Development track (GPA 3.5)
- Minor in Psychology
- University Honors Program

### Extra-Curricular

#### ORGANIZER OF REVOLUTIONUC AND MAKEUC

(Sep 2019 – Current)

- Organizer for UC's largest hackathons
- Developing and managing the hackathon website, server, database, and the various online services

#### PRESIDENT OF IT STUDENT ASSOCIATION

(Apr 2021 – Apr 2022)

- President for UC's largest student organization for IT students
- Providing weekly educational and networking opportunities to enthusiastic students

## **EXECUTIVE MEMBER OF ACM@UC**

(May 2019 – Apr 2021)

- Managing and updating the organization's website
- Plan and record biweekly tech talks and workshops

## **EXECUTIVE MEMBER OF THE UC ROTARACT CLUB**

(Oct 2018 – Oct 2021)

- Hosting on-campus events and off-campus volunteering projects
- Collaborating with the Rotary Club for networking and professional development events

AVAILABLE CO-OP FALL 2022, FULL-TIME MAY 2023